Cheo Roman

Software Developer

cheo.roman@gmail.com cheor.github.io github.com/CheoR linkedin.com/in/cheo-roman

I am a mixture of formal CS education, self-taught, bootcamp, and some professional experience at a start-up as a full-stack developer. I pivoted careers from a combined decade in the transportation/logistics/shipping industries to software development as a full stack developer. Let's connect and build great products together!

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript	React	Node	MongoDB
Python	Django	Figma	PostgresSQL
Git	Express	Material-UI	GraphQL
TypeScript	Heroku	Knex	Redis

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School

01/2021 — 06/2021

Nashville, TN

Coursework: Full Stack Software Development

NSS is a six-month intensive, full-time software development bootcamp focusing on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and server-side fundamentals with Python and Django.

- Developed full stack dynamic single-page applications with full CRUD functionality, utilizing vanilla JavaScript ES6+, HTML, CSS and React.js frontend and json-server/PostgreSQL backend
- Collaborated remotely in teams to build 6 group projects from wireframes/user stories in sprints
- Used GitHub for version control and GitHub Projects to plan, manage, review, and close issue tickets, adopting Agile development strategies like Scrum and Kanban
- Designed entity relationship diagrams (ERD) to build databases and define relationships, emphasizing flat data structures
- Styled applications using CSS, Bootstrap, reactstrap, and Material UI

Personal Projects

ShipItOut - Nashville Software School Full Stack Capstone

CRUD App displays shipping information in a minimalist dashboard style. Follow up to <u>PackItUp</u> in supply chain logistics/moving. Frontend/backend hosted on Heroku.

- SPA using React, HTML, CSS, Grid, Material-UI frontend and Python, Django/PostgreSQL backend
- Multiple users can apply CRUD actions on bookings/shipping containers, depending on their role in the container's movement from warehouse to oversea destinations
- User can filter/search tables by column features

PackItUp - Nashville Software School Backend Capstone

CRUD App tracks what users pack in boxes. Boxes/moves aggregate and update their information as the user updates their contents. Revamping project to use MongoDB, Express and Node.

- SPA using React, HTML, CSS, Grid and Flexbox frontend and json-server backend
- App helps users log shipping/storage box's contents
- V2 will include QRcodes, image capture, option to submit box info to **ShipItOut** and schedule delivery

BeerMe - Beer Recommender using Machine Learning - No longer maintained

CRUD App uses machine learning to recommend users new beers based on their preferences and/or beer attributes.

- SPA using React, HTML, SCSS, Grid, Flexbox frontend, PostgreSQL/Gunicorn/DRF/Django backend
- Developed using TDD, Jest/Enzyme frontend and Nose/Selenium backend
- Uses k-means clustering to recommend beers based on the user's preferences

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

InstantTeams	04/2022 — 07/2022
Jr. Full Stack Developer	Nashville, TN
Nashville Software School	02/2022 — 04/2022
Teaching Assistant	Nashville, TN
APL	03/2019 — 12/2020
Cargo Services Export/Import Clerk	Nashville, TN
Home Depot	01/2017 — 08/2018
Order Fulfillment Specialist, Interim Supervisor, Associate Coach, Safety Captain	Madison, TN
Enterprise Rent-A-Truck	06/2010 — 06/2016
Business Analyst/Rental Associate/Administrative Clerk	San Jose, CA
EDUCATION	
Nashville Software School	01/2021 — 06/2021
Coursework: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Python, Django, SQL	Nashville, TN
San Jose State University	09/2011 — 06/2012
Coursework: Python, Computational Linguistics	San Jose, CA
De Anza Community College	08/2010 — 06/2013
Coursework: Systems Programming, C, C++, Perl, Java, Web Design, Project Management	Cupertino, CA
Santa Ana Community College	08/2009 — 12/2009
Coursework: Web Design, International Business	Santa Ana, CA
University of Santa Cruz - Santa Cruz	08/2004 — 06/2009
Bachelor of Arts in Linguistics	Santa Cruz, CA